the following content is provided under a Creative Commons license
以下内容是根据Creative Commons授权提供
your support will help MIT OpenCourseWare continue to offer
您的支持将有助于麻省理工学院开放式课程继续报价
high-quality educational resources for free
免费优质教育资源
to make a donation or view additional materials from hundreds of them IT
进行捐赠或查看附加材料由数百人资讯
courses
课程
visit MIT OpenCourseWare at 0 CW
参观麻省理工学院开放式课程在0 CW
that MIT that EDU home for the
麻省理工学院的EDU回家
in
the
该
the in
在该
in
the
该
are the
是
in the last lecture we begin
在我们开始最后的演讲
the discussion love modulation and in particular what we focused on
讨论爱情的调制，特别是我们的重点是什么
was the continuous-time case and in talking about continuous-time modulation
是连续时间的情况下，并在谈到连续时间调制
we covered a number of topics we talked about
我们讨论了一些话题我们谈论
the properties and analysis love
的属性，并分析爱情
modulation when we had a complex exponential
调制时，我​​们有一个复杂的指数
carrier signal we talked about the properties and analysis in the case of a
载波信号，我们谈到了在一个案件的性质和分析
sinusoidal carrier
正弦载波
and in that context and related to
在这方面，并与
the application associated with communications
与通信相关联的应用程序
we talked about synchronous modulation
我们谈到了同步调制
a synchronous modulation and
同步调制和
also the notion love single sideband
也是概念爱单边带
modulation in
调制
the lecture today there are to issues that I'd like to address broad topics
今天的讲座有到，我想，以解决广泛的主题问题
one is Acer parallel discussion
一个是宏碁平行讨论
particularly is associated with complex exponential sinusoidal modulation
特别是与复指数正弦调制相关
for discrete-time signals and
对于离散时间信号和
the second is the introduction and analysis
二是介绍和分析
love a another kind of carriers specifically a post kind of carrier
爱一个另一种运营商的具体职位一种载体
in continuous time leading to the notions of pulse amplitude modulation
在连续时间导致脉冲幅度调制的概念
and eventually a very powerful theramin result called the sampling there
最终一个非常强大的theramin结果称为采样有
well let me begin the lecture though focusing on
也让我开始讲课，虽然重点
the discrete-time modulation to essentially
离散时间调制，以基本上
draw your attention to the fact dead the analysis and discrete-time
提请您注意以下事实：死者的分析和离散时间
very much parallels the analysis in continuous-time
非常多的相似之处分析在连续时间
well let's consider in the discrete-time
好让我们考虑在离散时间
case just as we had in continuous-time a
情况正如我们在连续时间
signal modulating a carrier signal
信号调制载波信号
and the resulting modulated signal
和由此产生的调制信号
is why event and it was
是为什么事件，这是
in continuous-time the modulation property
在连续时间的调制特性
Associated with the four EA transform dead
相关的四个EA变换死
provided the basis for the analysis and exactly the same thing is true in a
提供了基础的分析和完全一样的东西是真实的
discrete-time
离散时间
case in particular what we have in discrete-time
情况特别是我们所拥有的离散时间
is the modulation property as it relates to the Fourier transform
是调制特性，因为它涉及到傅立叶变换
which tells us that the four EA transform of the modulated signal
这告诉我们，4 EA变换的调制信号的
is the convolution all the
是卷积所有
for a transformer the carrier and the 48 transform or
用于变压器的载体和48变换或
the modulating signal and the only real difference in issue here
调制信号，并在这里问题的唯一真正的区别
is that in the discrete-time case
是，在离散时间情况
what we're talking about is a periodic
我们正在谈论的是一个周期
convolution because the specter of course a periodic
卷积因为课程的幽灵周期性
whereas in a continuous-time case it was an a periodic convolution so let's
而在一个连续时间情况下，它是一个周期性卷积让我们
parallel the discussion and in particular what will focus on
平行的讨论，特别是如何将专注于
is first a complex exponential
首先是一个复杂的指数
carrier and second a
载体和第二一
sinusoidal carrier and we'll see how this parallels our discussion in
正弦载波，我们将看到如何这相当于我们在讨论
continuous-time
连续时间
and will make fairly brief reference as we introduce
并会相当简短的参考为我们介绍
the post carrier for continuous-time will bring make very brief reference to
后载体连续时间会带来做出非常简短地提到
the post carrier for discrete-time
后载体离散时间
indicating that again the analysis and discrete-time and continuous-time
指示再次进行分析和离散时间和连续时间
is very parallel soul let's first consider
很平行的灵魂让我们首先考虑
complex exponential and sinus all carriers
复指数和鼻窦所有运营商
for the discrete-time case emphasizing
对于离散时间情况下，强调
the very strong parallel and similarity between
之间很强的并行性和相似性
discrete-time and continuous-time well
离散时间和连续时间以及
we have once again the modulation property
我们再次调制特性
and the modulation property tells us that the spectrum
和调制属性告诉我们，频谱
all the modulated signal is the periodic
所有的调制信号是周期性
convolution love the two spectra
卷积爱两个光谱
and let's consider for example
让我们考虑例如
an input for modulating spectrum as i've indicated here
一个输入，用于调制频谱，因为我已经在这里表示
and since we what to consider first the fall
因为我们什么首先考虑的秋天
a complex exponential carrier
复指数载波
will consider the case of CNN
将考虑美国有线电视新闻网的情况下，
equal to each to the J Omega subsea
等于每到歼欧米茄海底
n and let me stress by the way as
n和我想强调的方式
I did in the continuous-time case
我在连续时间的情况下做
dead out 10 to suppress the phase angle which of course can be associated with
死了10来抑制这当然可以与相关的相位角
the carrier also
承运人也
alright so we have then the spectrum
好吧，所以我们有那么谱
%uh the modulating signal the spektr the carrier signal
％呃调制信号的SPEKTR载波信号
if this is the carrier then its spectrum is an impulse train
如果是这样的载体，然后它的频谱是一个脉冲串
and then imposed strain I've indicated
然后施加应变，我表示
here and let me stress also that in
在这里，让我也强调，在
the discrete-time case of course the spectra
当然，在离散时间情况下的频谱
and all of the spektr involved are periodic with period of two pi
和所有涉及的SPEKTR是周期性的，两个PI期
so this then is the spectrum of the carrier signal
所以这则是载波信号的频谱
this is the spectrum the input signal the periodic convolution if these two
这是频谱的输入信号的周期性卷积如果这两个
is the spektr on the modulated signal and the result
是对调制信号的SPEKTR和结果
is then this spectrum shifted
然后这个频谱转移
to center frequency which is the carrier frequency
到中心频率的载波频率
Omega subsea so
欧米茄海底所以
the result love modulation with a complex exponential
结果爱调制与复指数
is a straightforward shifted the spectrum
是一个简单的转移频谱
to a carrot to so that what occurred around
以胡萝卜，以使发生什么左右
zero frequency now occurs around the frequency Omega subsea
零频率现在周围发生的频率欧米茄海底
now in the continuous-time k sweetie modulated
现在在连续时刻k亲爱的调制
with the case when we had a complex exponential carrier weedy modulated
用时，我们有一个复指数载波调制杂草丛生的情况下
by essentially just shifting the spectrum back
由本质上只是转移频谱背
and he in fact in the discrete-time case were able to do exactly the same thing
他其实在离散时间情况下能够做同样的事情
so if we work to replace
因此，如果我们的工作，以取代
see a van which is huge and make a subsidy and
看到一辆面包车这是巨大的，并作出补贴，
by see a very cozy the minus J Omega
通过看一个非常舒适的零下Ĵ欧米茄
CN the resulting spectrum
CN由此产生的频谱
would be an impulse train
将是一个脉冲串
as i indicate here and
我在此说明，并
the result all multiply why I have an
结果所有的繁殖，为什么我有一个
by that new carrier
由新运营商
in the frequency domain is a convolution if these two
在频域中是一个卷积如果这两个
and its relatively straightforward to verify that
和它相对简单，以验证
if you can follow these for the periodic convolution
如果你能遵循这些为周期卷积
then that will get us back to the original spectrum that we started with
然后，将让我们回到我们开始与原始光谱
so what's happened in the discrete-time case for the complex exponential
所以发生了什么事在离散时间情况下的复指数
is exactly the same as in continuous-time
是完全一样的连续时间
namely we might too late that corresponds to shifting the spectrum
即我们可能为时已晚，对应于移动频谱
weedy modulate by multiplying by the complex conjugate
杂草调制由复共轭相乘
the original modulating care the original carrier
原调制关心的原始载体
and that shifts the spectrum back to where it was originally
并转移频谱回到它最初是
okay now let's consider the case of a sinusoidal carrier in discrete-time
好吧，现在让我们考虑一个正弦载波的离散时间的情况下，
and again things very much parallel
又一次的东西非常多并行
what we saw in continuous-time
我们在连续时间看到
and again as we look at the specter
并再次，我们看看幽灵
I will choose a phase angle 0
我会选择一个相位角0
mainly for notational an analytical convenience
主要表现为符号上的便利性分析
so in this case now rather than
所以在这种情况下，现在，而不是
a carrier signal which is a single complex exponential
这是一个单一的复指数载波信号
it's now a sinusoidal carrier and the sinus or carrier is the summer too
它现在是一个正弦载波和窦或载体是夏天太
complex exponentials
复指数
and so if we consider a modulating spectrum that is the specter affects a
所以，如果我们考虑一个调制频谱是幽灵会影响
van
的
as something are the type that I indicate here
因为东西都是我在此说明的类型
and the spectrum of the carrier
和载波的频谱
now since the carrier is sign a soil rather than
现在由于承运人签订的土壤，而不是
a complex exponential consists of two impulses
复指数由两个脉冲
wanted pasta makers see and one at minus Omega subsea
想面食制造商看到，一个在零下欧米茄海底
convolved ing this spectrum with this spectrum
卷积ing这个频谱与此谱
gives us a replication affective Omega
给了我们一个复制情感欧米茄
around plus and minus Omega subsea
周围加号和减号欧米茄海底
and incidently with an ample to change a hair
顺便说一句，并具有充足的改变发型
so again things have
如此反复的事情有
worked as they did in continuous-time
工作，因为他们在连续时间做
in continuous time or in discrete-time
在连续的时间或在离散时间
modulating with a sinusoidal carrier
用正弦载波调制
with then correspond to a replication of the spectrum
然后用对应于频谱的复制
around plus the carrier frequency and replication the spectrum
周围加上载波频率和复制的频谱
around minus the carrier frequency in both cases
围绕减去在这两种情况下，载波频率
as long as the carrier frequency is large enough compared with the band with
只要载波频率足够大，以与带相比
the signal
信号
so that those two replications don't overlap
使那些重复两次不重叠
then its reasonable to suppose
那么它的合理的假设
that we should be able to recover the original signal
我们应该能够恢复原始信号
well in fact to d modulate
还有其实到D调制
in the discrete-time case we would again
在离散时间情况下，我们会再次
follow very much the strategy that we did in continuous-time
遵循非常多，我们在连续时间做了策略
in particular let's consider the modulating
特别是我们考虑的调制
by taking the modulated signal
通过利用调制后的信号
and again putting it through modulator again
并再次重新把它通过调制器
with a carrier which is co-signed Omega CN
用载体，其是共同署名欧米茄CN
if we do that we have a the modulator
如果我们这样做，我们有一个调制器
or what will turn out to be part of the modulator as i indicate here
还是什么会变成是调制器的一部分，我在此说明
the spectrum or the import signal
频谱或进口信号
is as I had just developed a replication
是因为我刚刚研制出的复制
up the original spectrum around plus and minus Omega subsea
周围加上原有的频谱和减号欧米茄海底
with an amplitude of the hair when this
与头发的振幅时这
is again convolved with the spectrum
再次卷积谱
love the carrier then
爱的载体，然后
we get a replication of the original spectrum
我们得到的原始光谱的复制
first around zero frequency as i indicate here
第一零频率附近，因为我在此说明
and then around twice the carrier frequency
然后围绕两倍的载波频率
and minus twice the carrier frequency
和减去两倍的载波频率
and as long as the carrier frequency
只要载波频率
is large enough compared with the
与相比足够大
with of the original signal day and as you can see
与原始信号日子，正如你可以看到
by extracting this part of the spectrum
通过提取该部分的频谱
with the low-pass filter we can in principle
与低通滤波器，我们可以在原则上
recover the spectrum associated with the original signal
恢复与原来的信号相关联的频谱
and again justice in continuous-time because this amplitude is a half
又在连续时间正义因为这个幅度是一个半
we would want to choose for scaling purposes
我们会想选择缩放的目的
a low-pass filter ample to which is
一个低通滤波器，以充足这是
to to compensate for this factor in the hair
在头发来弥补这个因子
so once again things work at basically
所以再次的东西在工作基本上
the same way as they had in continuous-time
因为他们在连续时间以同样的方式
we have sinusoidal modulation
我们有正弦调制
which consists love using a sinusoidal carrier
其中使用一个正弦载波组成的爱
and we have the the modulator
而我们也有调制器
which consists of taking the modulated signal
其中包括服用的调制信号
multiplying by the carrier and then
由承运人相乘，然后
processing Matt with a low-pass filter
用低通滤波器处理马特
to extract the portion of the spectrum
以提取频谱的一部分
which is around zero frequency as i indicate in the spectra below
这是零频率附近当i表示在下面的光谱
and the result then with this low pass filter having a gain of two
其结果再与该低通滤波器具有两个增益
is that we've recovered the original spectrum
是，我们已经恢复了原来的频谱
exit Omega which is the spectrum
退出欧米茄这是频谱
that we started now
我们现在开始
several other things to stress this is a fairly quick
其他的几件事情要强调这是一个相当快的
to we're through sinusoidal modulation for discrete-time
以我们正在通过正弦调制的离散时间
in there are very similar issues that arise in
在那里是出现非常相似的问题
the discrete-time case in terms of love having faced synchronization
离散时间情况下，在爱情方面已经面临着同步
and frequency synchronization between the modulator and demodulator
和调制器和解调器之间的频率同步
and we had discussed that in a fair amount of detail for the continuous-time
我们已经讨论过，在细节相当数量的连续时间
case in some sense in practical terms
案件在实践中的一些感
that becomes much more than issue in continuous-time
这变得比问题连续时间多
than it does in discrete-time in part because
它比在离散时间中的一部分，因为
synchronization between a modulator and demodulator
调制器和解调器之间的同步
is often much harder in a continuous-time
常常是在一个连续时间更难
system which is essentially an analog system
系统，它本质上是一种模拟系统
as compared with a digital system another
与数字系统中的另一个比较
very important reason and it's important to stress this at the outset
很重要的原因，并在一开始就强调这是很重要的
is that whereas the theory involving
是，而涉及的理论
the use of complex exponentials sinusoidal modulation
使用复杂的指数函数正弦调制
parallels very strongly in the continuous-time
相似之处很强烈的连续时间
and the discrete-time case in practical terms
和离散时间情况下，在实用方面
it has much more significance in continuous-time
它具有在连续时间更重要
than it does in discrete-time that is the notion
它比在离散时间即是概念
love sinusoidal modulation in the context of communication systems
爱正弦调制的通信系统的上下文中
is extremely important for continuous-time systems
对于连续时间系统极其重要的
and less so in discrete-time systems
而较少的离散时间系统
now kinda as a preview of a point to be raise later on
现在还挺作为一个点的预览待提高以后
I should modify that slightly with the statement
我要修改略有声明
that one very important plays in which
，一个很重要的戏剧中，
sinusoidal modulation in a discrete-time context the rises
正弦调制在离散时间情况下的上升
is in a class of systems called trance multiplexers or trans modulation systems
是一类系统称为恍惚多路复用器或反调制系统
and this surface is basically because
而这面基本上是因为
so many communication systems are now
这么多的通信系统现在
becoming digital and specifically discrete-time although the actual
成为数字和具体的离散时间虽然实际
transmission is continuous time
传输是连续的时间
the signal processing manipulation switching
信号处理操作切换
is discrete-time it so in fact it turns out
是离散时间了所以其实它原来
to be very important and useful to take
取是非常重要和有用的
a discrete-time representation I love
离散时间表示我爱
the analog signals a continuous-time signals
该模拟信号的连续时间信号
and in a discrete-time or digital representation
并在离散时间或数字表示
convert them from one modulation scheme
从一个调制方案，将它们转换
41 multiplexing scheme to another and
41复用方案到另一个
although I said a lot there that
虽然我说了很多那里，
really requires much more detail to
真的需要更多的细节
to develop in any in any sense at all
以发展任何在任何意义
you should come to get the notion that that discrete-time
你应该得到的概念，即离散时间
modulation systems become very important
调制系统就变得非常重要
in part because or implementation Elis use
部分原因是因为实施或使用伊利斯
okay now there is another application
还好现在有另一个应用程序
dead we have discussed for both continuous time actually previously for
死了，我们两个连续的时间实际上前面所讨论
discrete-time
离散时间
amplitude modulation with sinusoidal or complex exponential carriers
振幅调制正弦或复指数携带者
and let me just remind you that because in fact it becomes a very important one
让我提醒你，因为事实上它成为一个非常重要的一个
in the case love discrete-time systems
在爱的情况下离散时间系统
and that is the notion love using
就是用这一概念的爱
modulation together with fixed filtering
调制连同固定过滤
to implement a filter which is
实现一个过滤器，它是
which either has a variable cut off or
这已经不是一个变量切断或
converts let's say a low-pass filter to a high pass filter
皈依假设一个低通滤波器到高通滤波器
we originally talked about this when we introduce the modulation property
我们原来谈过这个时候我们引入调制特性
in the context of converting a low-pass filter
在转换的低通滤波器的情况下
to a high pass filter and the notion was
到一个高通滤波器和所述概念是
that if we modulate the signal
如果我们调制信号
with a carrier which is -1 to the end and that's just simply complex
与运营商是-1到结束，这只是简单的复杂
exponential
指数
or sinusoidal carrier with a carrier frequency of pie
或正弦载波与馅饼的载波频率
than that in effect interchanges the low frequencies in the high frequencies
比作用互换的高频率的低频率
and if and after modulation
而如果和后调制
that is processed with a low pass filter
一个与低通滤波器处理
and then the result is d modulated
然后将结果为d的调制
using exactly the same carrier namely a carrier which is
使用完全相同的载体即一种载体，它是
-1 to the end
-1至结束
then the effective that is equivalent
那么有效，它等效
to high-pass filtering on the original signal
对原始信号的高通滤波
and a generalization a bad would involve instead a
和泛化不好会牵扯而不是
this specific choice if -1 to the end
这个特定的选择，如果-1到年底
would involve a choice in general or the e to the J Omega sed CNN
将涉及在一般的选择或e来歼欧米茄sed的美国有线电视新闻网
that is a more general carrier frequency and
这是一种更一般的载波频率和
d modulator which is either the minus J
ð调制器，要么是负Ĵ
Omega subsea and and as i've represented here
欧米茄海底和和我在这里代表
and as we had talked about it when we talked about the modulation property for
当我们谈论了它，当我们谈到调制属性
discrete-time signals
离散时间信号
we had specifically chosen the conversion of a low pass to a high pass
我们曾专门选择了一个低通转换到高通
filter
过滤器
well let me continue the review of that
好让我继续的，审查
just by reminding you of the details of what happens with the spectra
只是提醒与光谱发生了什么细节你
and specifically the notion
和具体的概念
if we take this particular case omega-6 equal
如果我们把这种特殊情况下ω-6等于
to pie or covertly a carrier signal which is -1 to the end
以饼图或变相是-1到最后一个载波信号
then if we have the original spectra
然后，如果我们有原始光谱
and the specter all
和所有的幽灵
specter of the carrier signal the spectrum of the carrier signal
载体的幽灵信号中的载波信号的频谱
convolved with this spectrum
卷积与此谱
will then in effect shift this by
然后在效果由该转移
pie and so after
馅饼等后
modulating the result that we have is
调节的结果，我们已经是
shifted that spectrum so that what happened at low frequencies now happens
转移频谱，以便发生了什么事在低频现在发生
at high frequencies namely around pie
在高频段，即围绕馅饼
and what happens at what happened at high frequencies now happens
什么发生了什么在高频情况现在发生
at low frequencies well if thats process now
在低频好，如果现在那过程
with a low pass filter and this dashed line indicates the low-pass filter
用一个低通滤波器，该虚线表示的低通滤波器
then the result that we get is shown here
那么我们得到的结果如下所示
where we've extracted the low-frequency portion of the modulated signal
其中，我们已经提取的调制信号的低频部分
and now when we modulate or D modulate back
而现在，当我们调节或D调节回
then this spectrum is shifted back to where it belongs
然后该频谱偏移回到它属于
namely its shifted back to be centered around
即其移回要围绕中心
minus pie and around plus Park
减去馅饼和周围加上公园
so if we just compare this spectrum
所以，如果我们只是比较这谱
with the original spectrum at the top
在顶部的原始光谱
what we can see is that in effect what we've done
我们可以看到的是，实际上我们做了什么
is to extract a portion of the spectrum
是提取频谱的一部分
acquittal and the processing with a high pass filter
无罪释放和加工用的高通滤波器
and again this is very similar to what we did in continuous-time
并且再次，这是非常类似于我们在连续时间做
and all of the kinda analytical processes and
和所有的还挺分析过程和
and convolutions involved are very much the same
并参与卷积是大同小异
really the biggest difference between continuous-time and discrete-time
真正连续时间和离散时间的最大区别
has to do not so much with the details of the analysis but
已经做了详细的分析结果没有这么多，但
perhaps has more to do with issues
也许有更多的是与问题
love are practical applications
爱是实际应用
okay well so what we've done
好舒服，所以我们做了什么
so far for continuous-time and discrete-time
迄今为连续时间和离散时间
is to talk about modulation amplitude modulation
就是谈调制调幅
with complex exponential and sinus or carriers
与复指数及鼻窦或带菌者
we saw that the analysis is very similar although
我们看到的分析是非常相似的，虽然
applications are slightly different and now what I'd like to turn to
应用程序略有不同，现在我想谈谈
is a different choice love
是一种不同的选择爱
carrier signal and the carrier signal in this particular case
载波信号，并在此特定情况下的载波信号
is a post rain rather than
是一个后雨，而不是
a sinusoidal signal now
现在的正弦信号
the idea is the following
这个想法是以下
in general of course the modulator
在一般的过程中的调制器
it consists all multiplying x50
它包含了所有X50乘以
by whatever the carrier signal is and
由任何上述载波信号是与
previously we've talked about a carrier signal which is sinusoidal
之前我们已经谈过它是一个正弦载波信号
the carrier signal that we want to consider now
我们现在要考虑的载波信号
is a carrier signal which in fact is
是这实际上是一个载波信号
a pulse train and so in fact
一个脉冲串，所以实际上
what we want to do is multiply the input signal
我们想要做的是什么乘以输入信号
by a Paul strain and in effect then
由保罗应变和效果则
the modulated signal consists
经调制的信号由
of the original signal simply with time slices pulled out a bit as i've
原始信号简单地用时间片拉出了一下，因为我已经
indicated in the bottom Kurt
在底部库尔特表示
so what we have now
所以我们现在
is a modulated signal
是一个调制信号
that is a chopped or sliced version
这是一个切碎或切片版本
love the original waveform and
爱情原来的波形和
think that is what's referred to as pulse amplitude modulation
认为是什么被称为脉冲幅度调制
now it seems like it's kinda crazy idea any ideas
现在好像它有点疯狂的想法任何想法
search opt-out slices away form and
搜索退出切片离开的形式和
the hope that you can kinda put things back together again
希望你能有点把东西重新结合在一起
and the amazing thing about it is we'll see is that in fact
而令人惊奇的是，我们将看到的是，其实
under fairly broad general and applicability
在相当广泛的通用性和适用性
conditions you really can put the way for back together again
你的条件真的可以把这样的再聚首
if you just have these times places
如果你只是有这些时间地点
not only that but that basic notion
不仅如此，但这一基本概念
as we'll see is independent in fact
正如我们将看到的事实是独立的
up with the with the those time slices or effect the with can go to zero
与该用那些时间片或起可以到零
and in fact we're going to make the with go to zero and really only dependent
而事实上，我们要做出与去零，真的只有依赖
on what the frequency love the polls trainers
在什么样的频率热爱教练投票
so let's explore that in some detail
所以让我们来探讨一些细节
and what we want to look at is the analysis but let me
我们想了解一下什么是分析，但让我
let me first just comment very briefly there
让我先回应只是很简单的有
all the analysis we go through as has been true in the case a sinusoidal
所有我们经历的一直是在真实的情况下正弦分析
modulation all the analysis that we go through
调制一切，我们经过分析
holes just as well with
孔一样好
especially minor analytical modifications to
特别是轻微的分析修改
discrete-time pulse amplitude modulation as it does to
离散时间脉冲幅度调制，因为它不
continuous-time pulse amplitude modulation
连续时间脉冲幅度调制
and so will really only go through this
等会真的只有通过这个
in terms of tracking the way for inspector for the continuous-time
在对连续时间跟踪的方式对检测器的条件
case but bear in mind that the results are basically similar
如此，但要记住，结果基本相似
for discrete-time okay well
对于离散时间也没关系
let's see how we get the basic result
让我们来看看如何得到基本的结果
that we want to get
我们希望得到
what we have is a
我们所拥有的是一个
modulating signal which is a pulse train basically a square wave
调制信号，该信号是一个脉冲序列基本上是一个方波
and as we've seen in previous lectures the spectra
正如我们在以前的讲座见过的光谱
or Fourier transform associated with that is an impulse train
或傅立叶变换与该关联是一个脉冲串
and the envelope that impulse train
并在信封冲动列车
is over for over sin x over X function
已经结束了罪x在X功能
the four th transform is impulses and the spacing of the impulses
四个次变换是冲动和冲动的间距
is Associated with the fundamental frequency
相关联的基频
all the Paul strain and thats Omega Sappi so make it appears to pride
所有的保罗应变和多数民众赞成欧米茄塞佩因此使它显得骄傲
divided by the period
由周期划分
the pulse train and at the
脉冲序列，并在
amplitude and shape but this envelope is dictated
振幅和形状，但这种包络决定
by that parameter Delta
通过该参数三角洲
which has to do with how wide the pulses are
这是因为有脉冲的宽度是
okay so we have a time function
好了，我们有一个时间函数
it's multiplied by this post rain now we're talking continuous-time
它乘以这个帖子雨现在我们谈论的连续时间
so in the frequency domain
这样在频域
we have the Fourier transform the time function convolved with
我们有傅里叶变换进行卷积以时间函数
this Fourier transform for the pulse train and let's see what that looks like
这傅立叶变换的脉冲串，让我们看看是什么样子
if we were to consider let's say
如果我们考虑让我们说
a Fourier transform which I A kinda chosen is more or less a general one
一傅里叶变换IA有​​点儿选择是或多或少一般1
then in fact when we can follow this
那么实际上，当我们可以按照这个
with this simple strain what we end up with
这个简单的应变是我们结束了
is a replication all
是复制所有
this spectrum at
此谱
the places in the frequency domain
在频域中的地方
where the individual impulses occurred
在那里发生的个人冲动
so we can see that this spectrum is replicated at each's
所以我们可以看到，这个频谱被复制在每个的
these locations and as long as
这些位置并且只要
the frequency
频率
above the post-training is large enough compared
上面比较了培训后的足够大
with a maximum frequency in the
用在最高频率
original single X if T so that there is no overlap between these triangles
如果T原单个X，以便有这些三角形之间没有重叠
then what you can see in fact somewhat amazingly
那么你其实可以看到有些令人惊讶
is dead simply by low-pass filtering the result
是死简单地通过低通滤波的结果
we can get back except for an amplitude factor
我们可以回去，除了振幅因数
we can give get back to the original signal
我们可以给返回到原始信号
now it's amazing it really is amazing
现在它是惊人的它确实是惊人的
dead all that this depends on
死了都，这取决于
is the original signal being banned limited
是原始信号被取缔有限
and the frequency the post-training be high enough
和频率的培训后有足够高
so that when you replicate the spectrum in the frequency domain
这样，当你复制的频谱在频域
is no overlap between these individual replications and will
正是这些个体的复制和意志之间没有重叠
have a dress that a little more in a few minutes
有一件衣服在几分钟内，一个多一点
but let me first the ball point out that
但让我先球指出，
this has a whole variety a very important implications
这有一个整体多种非常重要的意义
one is in the context of communications
一个是在通信的上下文中
it leads to another very important
这引出了另一个非常重要的
multiplexing scheme for communications we talked last time about
我们谈到最后一次关于复用方案的通信
frequency division multiplexing where individual signals were put into
频分复用，其中个别的信号被放进
individual frequency slots
单独的频率槽
by choosing different carrier frequencies for sinusoidal modulated
由正弦调制选择不同的载波频率
signal
信号
what this suggests is that what we can do
这是什么提示的是，我们能做些什么
is put the
被放置在
sons put different signals into
儿子把不同的信号转换成
non-overlapping time slots
非重叠的时隙
and in fact be able to recover the original signals back again
而实际上能够恢复原来的信号回来了
so in particular suppose that
所以特别是假设
I had a signal which I modulated with a pulse train
我有我调制的脉冲串信号
and I i chose another signal modulated with another poll strain
我我选择调制与另一民调应变另一个信号
where the time slot was different and I continue this process
其中时隙是不同的，我继续这一进程
and after the after i'd done this with some number of channels
和之后的之后我会与渠道一定数量做到了这一点
simply and it all those together
只是，这一切的在一起
as i indicate here then as long as I knew what time slots to associate with
我在此说明，然后只要我知道什么时段与结社
what signal
什么信号
I could get the original a
我能得到一个原
modulated signals back again
调制信号回来了
and then as long as the frequency 0
然后只要在频率0
the impulse train was such that
脉冲序列是这样的，
I was able to do this reconstruction
我能做到这一点重建
by simply low-pass filtering then
通过简单的低通滤波，然后
I would be able to be my Julie so it's a very different very important modulation
我将能够成为我的朱莉所以这是一个非常不同的非常重要的调制
scheme call time division
计划通话时间分割
multiplexing in contrast to frequency division multiplexing as we talked about
复而相比之下，频分复用，因为我们谈论
last time
上次
I made reference earlier the concept of Trance multiplexing and in fact
我参考了前面恍惚复用的概念，实际上
what happens in many communication systems
在许多通信系统发生了什么
is dead the signals are represented in fact
死了的信号表示，事实上
in discrete-time the analog continues time signals are represented in
在离散时间模拟持续时间信号表示为
discrete-time
离散时间
and very often the conversion from
而且往往从转换
frequency division multiplexing to time division multiplexing and back
频分复用时分多路复用及回
is done in fact in the discrete-time to me
做实际上在离散时间到我
okay so what we have then
好了，我们有什么，然后
is the notion
是概念
dead we can
死了，我们可以
multiply a time function
乘以一个时间函数
by a poll strain as i indicated here
以投票应变正如我在这里
and from the output I can
并从输出我可以
if the frequency this post rain is high enough in relation to this band with
如果频率这个帖子雨足够高有关此与乐队
from the output which consists of both
从它包括两个输出
time slices from those times places
从这些时间地点时间片
I can recover the original signal
我可以恢复原始信号
stressing again the reason it relates
再次强调它涉及的原因
to the spectra and
在光谱和
the reason is dead the original spectra
其原因是死者的原始光谱
is simply replicated at
简直是在复制
multiples all the fundamental frequency
倍数的所有基频
upholstery
内饰
now is a very important thing to observe here
现在是时候在这里看到一个非常重要的事情
which is dead the ability to do the reconstruction
这是死做灾后重建的能力
is associated with the notion of whether we can extract that
与我们是否可以提取概念相联系
kinda central triangle light happened choose a triangular shape but
事还挺中央三角形光选择一个三角形状，但
obviously I could be talking about any shape as long as it's been limited
很明显，我可以，只要它被限制在谈论任何形状
the ability to extract at and notice
提取能力，在与通知
that in this modulated output spectrum
在这种调制的输出频谱
the ability to recover this is totally independent
恢复这个能力是完全独立
all what the value of Delta is in other words
什么都三角洲的值是在换句话说
if we look back at
如果我们回头看
the modulator then
调制器则
in fact we can make Delta
其实我们可以把三角洲
the with these pulses arbitrarily small
在与这些脉冲任意小
and in theory that doesn't affect
而在理论上不影响
our ability to do the reconstruction now in practical terms it might
我们现在要做的重建工作实际上它可能能力
looking back once more at the specter of the output
回首输出的幽灵再次
noticed that this sample to is proportional to Delta
注意到，这个样品是成正比的三角洲
and what that suggests is that as we make
什么暗示是，当我们使
Delta smaller and smaller which we
增量小，我们
might in fact want to do if you want to time division multiplexed last two
实际上可能想要做的，如果你想时分复用最后两个
channels
渠道
in principle in theory you could make it an infinite number channels just by
在理论原则上你可以把它无限多渠道仅仅通过
making an infinitesimally small
做一个无穷小
the smaller it is in some sense the less energy there is and again
越小它在某种意义上是在较少的能量有和再次
in practical terms this one of those things if you push down here pops up
在实践中这一块的那些东西，如果你推下来这里弹出
there
那里
namely you eventually run into issues such as noise problems
也就是你最终遇到的问题，如噪音问题
so more more typically what's done is
所以更多更典型的是怎么做的
to in fact eliminate the scale factor a delta
到实际上消除了比例因子增量
and the way that that's done is very simply
和方式，这样做了很简单的
it's done by choosing
它通过选择完成
the with I love the pulses
在与我爱的脉冲
and the height %uh the pulses in such a way
和高度％呵以这样的方式中的脉冲
dead the area is constant even as
死者的面积更是为常量
we make Delta get arbitrarily small so
我们做出三角洲获得任意小，所以
and we can just modify our argument
我们可以只修改我们的观点
so that what we're referring to is a modulating post rain
让我们指的是什么调制后雨
which is a pulse train with positive with Delta
这是一个脉冲序列与台达积极
and height one over Delta in that case
在这种情况下，高一结束三角洲
as Delta gets arbitrarily small
作为台达得到任意小
then in fact what these rectangles become
那么其实这些东西变成矩形
are impulses in which case what we're talking about
是冲动在这种情况下我们在谈论
is a carrier signal
是载波信号
which in fact is an impulse train
这实际上是一个脉冲串
and the resulting modulated signal
和由此产生的调制信号
is and imposed strain for which the amplitudes
被征收和应变的振幅
of the impulses are proportional to
的冲动是成正比的
the original input waveform at
在原来的输入波形
the times at which these impulses occur
在这些冲动发生次
okay well let's look at the analysis a bat
还好还有让我们来看看分析的蝙蝠
and so now what we're talking about
所以现在我们正在谈论什么
is a spectrum
是一个光谱
dead up
死了
consists all the result
由所有的结果
love the spectrum we talked about before the sin x over X envelope except
爱我们谈到了罪x的基于X信封前，除了频谱
that now is Delta goes to zero that becomes
现在是三角洲趋于零的变
flat in other words the modulating signal is an impulse train
平换句话说，调制信号是一个脉冲串
and so as we look at the spectrum
因此当我们看谱
the modulating signal that is then
调制信号，然后将其
and impose train in the frequency domain the high
并处在频域火车高
is proportional to the frequency
正比于频率
up the impulse train and Omega the best now denotes
了脉冲串和欧米茄最好现在表示
the frequency the impulse train and
频率的脉冲序列，并
the resulting output the modulator
所得到的输出的调制器
has a spectrum which is
有一个频谱是
this original spectrum again replicated around
这种原始的频谱重新复制身边
each love these impulses in other words replicated in multiples
每个喜欢这些冲动的倍数复制换句话说
or the sampling frequency now
或现在的采样频率
this is very much identical to the more general case we have
这是非常相同的更一般的情况下，我们有
this replication the spectra
这个复制的光谱
and as long as
只要
this sample the the frequency of the impulse train is
这样的脉冲序列的频率是
large enough compared with the band with the signal
足够大，以与信号的频带相比
so that these triangles don't overlap
使这些三角形不重叠
I can extract this
我可以提取这个
portion of the spectrum by low-pass filtering
频谱由低通滤波部分
which in fact with then give us back
这实际上与当时还给我们
the original signal now
现在将原始信号
if instead this frequency Omega sed am
相反，如果这个频率欧米茄sed的正
is greater than Omega best minus Omega sed am
大于欧米茄最负欧米茄sed的正
we would have a spectrum that looked
我们将有一个谱，看上去
something more like this and what's happened
更多的东西像这样和发生了什么
in this case is that because
在这种情况下，由于
we have an overlap here we've destroyed the ability
我们有一个重叠在这里，我们已经摧毁的能力
to recover the original signal from the impulse train
从脉冲序列中恢复原始信号
and that would be true also in general in a more general case
这将是真也一般在一个更一般的情况
love pulse amplitude modulation with
爱情脉冲幅度调制
pulses that up 90 with
脉冲高达90与
this effect by the way is one that will be
这种效果的方式是1，这将是
exploring in considerably more detail in the next lecture and
探索更多的细节在下一讲及
it's a phenomenon or distortion referred to as a leasing which
它被称为租赁的现象或扭曲的
in fact is important and interesting topic but
其实是很重要的，有趣的话题，但
going back to the case in which we've chosen the frequency of the upholstery
回去在我们所选择的内饰频率的情况下，
in high enough
在足够高
then we would recover the original signal
那么我们就恢复原始信号
by processing it through
通过处理它
a low-pass filter
一个低通滤波器
and in in that case
并且在这种情况下
what this says is dead if we have a signal
这是什么说是死的，如果我们有一个信号
and we modulated with an impulse train
我们调制的脉冲串
if we then process that impulse train through an ideal ok pass filter
如果我们当时的过程，通过一个理想的确定通滤波器的脉冲串
given the right conditions on Sat on the frequency the impulse train and the band
给定的频率上周六在适当的条件的脉冲串和乐队
with the signal
与信号
we can recover the original signal back again
我们可以对原始信号中恢复回来
now let me stress just going back to
现在让我强调只是要回
the picture in which we have done this modulation
在我们做这种调制的图片
that this process where the modulation
这个过程在调制
where the carrier signal involves an impulse train is
其中载波信号涉及一种冲动火车
often referred to as sampling and
通常被称为采样和
what that mean specifically is dead
那是什么意思特别是死的
if we notice this resulting in polls train
如果我们注意到由此产生的民调列车
is in fact a sequence
实际上是在一个序列
all samples all
所有样品全部
the original continuous-time signal in other words
换句话说原来的连续时间信号
what we've done in effect is taken instantaneous samples at this way form
我们已经在做的效果是采取瞬时样品在这样的形式
and the implication is that if we do that
而其含意是，如果我们做到这一点
at a rapid and afraid in relation
在一个快速，恐怕就
to the band with the signal then
与信号的频带然后
we can in fact recover the original signal back again
我们其实是可以恢复原始信号回来了
and finally to remind you
最后提醒你
I'll the argument once more
我会的说法再一次
we have an original signal
我们有一个原始信号
and we have its spectrum when we've sampled it and this is now the sampled
我们有它的频谱时，我们已经采样了，这就是现在的采样
signal it's an impulse train whose instantaneous values
信号是一个脉冲串，其瞬时值
are samples at the original waveform the spectrum a bad
是频谱样本在原始波形坏
is the original one replicated
是原来的复制
and when that is processed through a
并且当一个通过一个处理
low-pass filter to extract this part of the spectrum
低通滤波器来提取该部分的频谱
then after the low-pass filter we can
那么低通滤波器，我们可以后
recover the original signal back again
回来恢复原始信号
okay well in fact me although
还好还有其实我虽然
a if you kinda follow through
一，如果你还挺循
the specter and the waveforms this all seems fairly
幽灵和波形这一切似乎相当
straightforward and perhaps
简单，也许
or perhaps not obvious
或者不明显
it's really worth reflecting on how amazing
它的真正价值体现在如何惊人
the result really is what it says we begin this discussion
结果真的是说话算数，我们开始这一讨论
by talking about modulation and in fact modulation and sinusoidal modulation is
通过谈论调制而事实上调制和正弦调制
important in its own right
在自己的权利重要
we ended the discussion by talking
我们通过谈话结束讨论
about first pulse amplitude modulation
关于第一个脉冲幅度调制
and then showing how under the right set of conditions
然后示出如何正确的一组条件下
you can in fact take away form and
其实你可以带走的形式和
sample it with a set of instantaneous samples
一组瞬时样品抽样它
and that said instantaneous samples in fact
并且，所述实际上瞬时样本
are sufficient totally represent and reconstruct the signal
是完全足够的代表和重构信号
what in fact the formal statement that is
什么实际上的正式声明是
is referred to as the sampling theorem
被称为采样定理
very powerful their own that says
非常强大的自己，说
if were given equally spaced samples over time function
如果给予等距样本随着时间的推移功能
and if that time function is band limited
如果那个时候的功能是频带有限
and if the band with
并且如果与带
or is or if this if this sampling frequency is
或者是，或者这一点，如果这个采样频率为
chosen in the right way in relation
在选择有关的正确方法
to the
到
band with then in fact
与当时乐队其实
the original time function is
原来时间功能
uniquely recoverable with a low-pass filter
唯一地收回与一个低通滤波器
now the sampling theorem is kinda
现在的采样定理是有点
I would say a watershed a cornerstone
我想说一个分水岭的基石
love a lot of the discussion we've been having
爱有很多，我们一直有讨论
for a whole variety of reasons if first of all crops out almost as kind as
整整各种各样的原因，如果首先作物出几乎一样样的
straightforward obvious statement but more importantly
直接的明显的语句，但更重要的是
what it says is dead
它说什么是死
if I have a continuous-time signal which satisfies the right-center conditions
如果我有满足的权利中心的条件下连续时间信号
I can represent it by what it does
我可以用它做什么它代表
at sampling instance or acquittal only at discrete
仅在离散采样实例或无罪释放
is this a time
这是一个时间
now what that leads to
现在是什么导致
is a whole host of things wanna which
是想要的东西一大堆的
is the statement that says if we have a continuous-time signal
是说，如果我们有一个连续时间信号的声明
I could in fact represented
我其实可以代表
as a discrete-time signal and I could even think
作为一个离散时间信号，我什至能想到
love processing a continuous-time signal
爱处理连续时间信号
using discrete time concepts
使用离散时间概念
and when I'm all done converting back through
而当我完成所有转换回通过
the power the sampling theorem converting back to a continuous-time
电源采样定理转换回一个连续时间
sick
生病
so the sampling theorem provides this
所以采样定理提供了这种
with a very major important bridge between
之间有一个非常重大的重要桥梁
continuous-time and discrete-time implementations and ideas
连续时间和离散时间实现方式和想法
in the next several lectures we will be exploring so this in considerable detail
在接下来的几次讲座，我们将探索所以这个相当详细
first the focus in more next time
首先在更多的下一次焦点
on some with the specific issues and distortions associated with sampling and
对一些与采样相关的具体问题和扭曲，
following that
以下是
a discussion are what is referred to as
讨论什么是被称为
discrete-time processing of continuous-time signals
连续时间信号的离散时间处理
thank you
谢谢